[
    {
        "id": 1,
        "answer": "(V * OG)/(avgP*E)",
        "question": "Total Pounds of Grain",
        "note": "example OG 80 for '1.080', V target volume in gallons, avgP is average PPPG of grist, E is effeciency"
    },
    {
        "id": 2,
        "answer": "(Final + Trub)/.96/.9 + (.133*W) + Equip",
        "question": "Total Water",
        "note": "W is pounds of grain"
    },
    {
        "id": 3,
        "answer": "4.6 + .3(W1*L1 + W2*L2 ...)/V",
        "question": "SRM > 10",
        "note": "W is pounds, L is Lovibond"
    },
    {
        "id": 4,
        "answer": "(W1*L1 + W2*L2 ...)/V",
        "question": "SRM < 10",
        "note": "W is pounds of grain, L is Lovibond"
    },
    {
        "id": 5,
        "answer": "(W * AA * U * 7490)/V",
        "question": "IBU for hop by weight/AA",
        "note": "W is ounces of hops, AA is alpha acid of hop, V is volume in gallons"
    },
    {
        "id": 6,
        "answer": "(IBU * V)/(AA * U * 7490)",
        "question": "Ounces of hops for addition",
        "note": "V is volume in gallons, AA is alpha acid of hop, U is utilization"
    },
    {
        "id": 7,
        "answer": ".2/R * (T2-T1) + T2",
        "question": "Strike Water Temperature",
        "note": "T1 is initial temperatture, T2 is target mash temperature, R is quarts of water per pound of grain"
    },
    {
        "id": 8,
        "answer": "1.5 * W/4",
        "question": "Strike Water Volume",
        "note": "W is pounds of grain"
    },
    {
        "id": 9,
        "answer": ".015 * V * OG",
        "question": "Liquid Yeast Packs (Lager)",
        "note": "example OG value: `80` for `1.080`"
    },
    {
        "id": 10,
        "answer": ".007 * V * OG",
        "question": "Liquid Yeast Packs (Ale)",
        "note": "example OG value: `80` for `1.080`"
    },
    {
        "id": 11,
        "answer": "(OG - FG) * .132",
        "question": "ABV",
        "note": "example OG value: `80` for `1.080`"
    }
]
